Laurence W. "Bill" Lane, Jr. papers, circa 1953-2010 M1811
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Laurence W. "Bill" Lane, Jr. papers, circa 1953-2010
circa 1953-1910
M1811
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
25.0 Linear feet
The papers include speeches, personal correspondence, and correspondence and documents relating to Lane Publishing Co., producers of Sunset Magazine, books, and films.
Lane, L.W. (Laurence William), 1919-2010
Biographical Note
Laurence William Lane Jr. often known as Bill Lane (November 7, 1919 - July 31, 2010) was an American magazine publisher and philanthropist. Bill Lane graduated from Stanford University in 1942. The Lane family owned and published Sunset Magazine. As their father (who died on February 20, 1967) phased himself out of the business, Bill took over the magazine publishing and brother Melvin (1922–2007) managed the book business. The Lane publishing business was sold to Time Warner in 1990. Bill Lane was the first mayor and one of the founders of Portola Valley, California, in 1964. From 1975–1976 he served as US Ambassador-at-large and lived in Japan. From 1985 to 1989 he was appointed US Ambassador to Australia and Nauru. The Lanes sponsored an internship program at the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution. In 2005 a donation to Stanford University endowed the multidisciplinary Center for the Study of the North American West. The Center reflects Lane's own interests, including involvement with cultural and environmental issues in the West.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Donna Jean Lane, 2011. Accession 2011-027.
Scope and Contents
The papers include speeches, personal correspondence, and correspondence and documents relating to Lane Publishing Co., producers of Sunset Magazine, books, and films.
California--History--1950-; California--History--1850-1950.; Sunset Magazine (Firm)
- Notre Dame, College of -- Honorary Fellow (Carton 1, Folder 1)
- Harvard Business School Assn. of N. Calif.: Annual Businessman/Statesman Award to Mel and Bill. April 8, 1976 (Carton 1, Folder 2)
- NACOA: National Advisory Committee on Oceansxand Atmosphere) 1972-1978[?] (Carton 1, Folder 3)
- Lane Family Background (Carton 1, Folder 4)
- Oral History Interview: Bruce Campbell Interviews with Bill McGrew, Lou Richardson, and Gen Callahan (Carton 1, Folder 5)
- Lou Richardson and Gen Callahan, 12/81 (Carton 1, Folder 6)
- Golden Cable Card Award to Bill Lane: San Francisco Advertising Club, May 16, 1985 (Carton 1, Folder 7)
- Asakawa, Minato; "A Study of Sunset Magazine," Masters Thesis, Stanford University, May 1978 (Carton 1, Folder 8)
- Misc. Pamphlets, Brochures on Lane Publications [1 of 2] (Carton 1, Folder 9)
- Misc. Pamphlets, Brochures on Lane Publications [1 of 2] (Carton 1, Folder 10)
- Lowell Thomas: Sunset 75th Anniversary Broadcast, May 14, 1973, 1/4" audiotape, 5" reel, with correspondence (Carton 1, Folder 11)
- General Company Background (Carton 1, Folder 12)
- Calfornia Historical Society: "the Early Sunset Magazine" recption, October, 1973 (Carton 1, Folder 13)
- DDT Issue (Carton 1, Folder 14)
- An Alliance That Survives: ANZUS, July 14, 1988 (Carton 1, Folder 15)
- "Walking in My Aussie Shoes," April 5, 1989 (Carton 1, Folder 16)
- The American-Austrlian Relationship 2/23-27/87 (Carton 1, Folder 17)
- Is the Australian-American relationship a Little Bit Crook?, 12/15/ 87 (Carton 1, Folder 18)
- Keynote Address - Cattle Council Conference - Canberra 5/5/86 (Carton 1, Folder 19)
- The Country Almanac, 7/6/88: "Bill Lane: update from Down Under" (Carton 1, Folder 20)
- Australian News Clippings, etc.; commentary (Carton 1, Folder 21)
- Colonial Williamsburg Journal, Autumn, 1987: "A Reflection of Williamsburg in Australia's Cap.[ital]" (Carton 1, Folder 22)
- The Washington Post Magazine, Oct 11, '87: Australia: Getting Out From Down Under." (Carton 1, Folder 23)
- The Bulletin, Feb. 21,1989, Page 91 (Carton 1, Folder 24)
- August 10 Barbecue (Carton 1, Folder 25)
- Misc. Australian clippings, publications (Carton 1, Folder 26)
- Special Projects (Carton 1, Folder 27)
- Sunset Written History (Carton 1, Folder 28)
- Lane Publishing Co. Art Collection (Carton 1, Folder 29)
- Maynard Dixon (Edith Hamlin) (Carton 1, Folder 30)
- Maurice Logan (Adolph-Humphrey) (Carton 1, Folder 31)
- Meth Fessel (Mullen/Stockton) (Carton 1, Folder 32)
- 1973 Series (Carton 1, Folder 33)
- Sunset Centennial 1998 (Carton 1, Folder 34)
- Organizing Committee for Preserving Sunset's Written and Oral History (Carton 1, Folder 35)
- Sunset Oral History Project (Carton 1, Folder 36)
- LWL Sr, Jr, and Mel [photos] (Carton 1, Folder 37)
- LWL Sr [photos, etc.] (Carton 1, Folder 38)
- Printers (Carton 1, Folder 39)
- Richardson/Callahan (Carton 1, Folder 40)
- Southern Pacific (Carton 1, Folder 41)
- Demo Gardens (Carton 1, Folder 42)
- Dedication New Building, November 1964 (Carton 1, Folder 43)
- Open House (Carton 1, Folder 44)
- Awards and Honors (Carton 1, Folder 45)
- Miscellaneous Lane Family Awards (Carton 1, Folder 46)
- California Mission Trails Salute to Lane Family - Jan 29, 1965 (Carton 1, Folder 47)
- Sunset's 75th Anniversary: January, May, and November Issues; "Ideas for Improving You Home;" "Here's Success" by Donnelley [all in document box] (Carton 2, Folder 1)
- Oral History Transcripts: 1978-1980 (Carton 2, Folder 2)
- "Who's Buying Now?," 1983 Marketing Film, Office print, 16mm film (Carton 2, Folder 3)
- "The Tropics: A Garden In Time," no date, 16mm film (Carton 2, Folder 4)
- The Press and It's Place in International Relations, 1941, Folder empty] (Carton 3, Folder 1)
- "Challenge in the Pacific" - Pacific Area Travel Conference, 3/13/1953 [also, "Tourism Can Build A Better Environment" - Pacific Basin Economic Council, May 1973] (Carton 3, Folder 2)
- Talk given at Magazine Industry Seminar - 7/20/64 (Carton 3, Folder 3)
- "Some Thoughts About Tourism from a Friend of Hawaii" - 12/12/64 (Carton 3, Folder 4)
- UNESCO Talk, Nov 24, 1969 (Carton 3, Folder 5)
- The Day the Tourists Stop Coming, September, 1969 (Carton 3, Folder 6)
- TTRA Talk in Monterey: "The Smokeless Industry," Aug 17, 1979 (Carton 3, Folder 7)
- "Publisher's View on the Challenge of Change," Audit Bureau of Circulations, 10/21/ 70 (Carton 3, Folder 8)
- Speech and Forms, WACTI, Membership list, 12/2/1970 (Carton 3, Folder 9)
- "Tourism: Opportunity with Responsibility," Pacific Basin Economic Cooperation Council (PBECC), 5/71 (Carton 3, Folder 10)
- "Parks, Man, and His Environment," National Parks Centennial, Nov/Dec 1971 (Carton 3, Folder 11)
- Speeches, National Park Service; Opening Comments, Press Mtg., NP Centennial Commission, 11/71 (Carton 3, Folder 12)
- National Parks: Guardians of Our Heritage, Mar 24, 1972 (Carton 3, Folder 13)
- Cows and Ecology, CA Cattlemen's Assn. Oakland, CA, 12/10/71 (Carton 3, Folder 14)
- Is Hawaii Breaking It's Promise? June 26, 1972 (Carton 3, Folder 15)
- Tourism Can Build a Better Environment, 4/13/73 (Carton 3, Folder 16)
- Magazines in the Total Media Mix, Oct 24, 1973 (Carton 3, Folder 17)
- Yes, Mr. Cole, I Would, Sept 10, 1974; Henry Johnson Fisher Award Luncheon (Carton 3, Folder 18)
- University of Nevada Talk, 5/9/74 (Carton 3, Folder 19)
- "Everythings Coming Up Roses, Maybe," 1/24/75 (Carton 3, Folder 20)
- Tourism: A Sound Economic Partner - Wellington, New Zealand, 4/9/75 (Carton 3, Folder 21)
- "Go West Young Man and Be Kind To IT," WSAAA Talk, 3/4/77 (Carton 3, Folder 22)
- The Second Chance, Gunn High School, 6/15/77 (Carton 3, Folder 23)
- "Tourism: A Sound Economic Partner and Good Environmental Influence," 4/9/75, New Zealand Travel Association (Carton 3, Folder 24)
- "PATA's Rich Heritage: Critical for a Sund Future," 1/25/78, PATA Conference, New Delhi (Carton 3, Folder 25)
- "Does the World Need a Travel Ethic," ASTA, Kailua - Kona, 4/28/8 (Carton 3, Folder 26)
- "Winning in the West - With Print," 7/10/78, Stanford U Publishing Course (Carton 3, Folder 27)
- "The Western Business Climate: Healthy and Growing," Japan-California Assoc, 8/3/78 (Carton 3, Folder 28)
- "Watching the West for Life Style," General Electric Consumer Sector Meeting, 10/1/78 (Carton 3, Folder 29)
- ABC Talk [Audit Bureau of Circulation] 11/6/78 (Carton 3, Folder 30)
- "The Phenomenon of the Western American Traveler, " Tokyo, Japan, 11/28/79 (Carton 3, Folder 31)
- "Tourism and the Three 'E's": Energy, Ecology, and Economy," Westerm Tourism Conference, Dec. 1979 (Carton 3, Folder 32)
- "Tourism: People-to-People Force for Peace" - May 29, 1980, PATA (Carton 3, Folder 33)
- "Western America: the Nation's Laboratory for the Future, " June 10, 1980, Western Governors' Conference (Carton 3, Folder 34)
- Honeymoon Over For Tourism, Oct 14-15, 1980, Grand Hyatt Hotel, NY (Carton 3, Folder 35)
- "The Inter-Relationship of Heritage Conservation and Tourism," July 22, 1982, Eas-West Center - Honolulu, Hawaii (Carton 3, Folder 36)
- "The USA Looks West to Japan," March 28,1983 (Carton 3, Folder 37)
- Burtenshaw Lecture Series: "Tourism hass Earned A Better Image," WSU, Nov. 17, 1983 (Carton 3, Folder 38)
- Opening Statement - Sen Foreign Relations Committee, 11/20/85 (Carton 3, Folder 39)
- Dedication of UCSC Aboretum Aust. Coll., Delivered by John Melhuish, 6/21/86 (Carton 3, Folder 40)
- "The Critical Role of Public Service," Commonwealth Club, 9/29/89 (Carton 3, Folder 41)
- "The Critical Role of Public Service," Churchill Club, holiday Inn, Palo Alto, 12/29/89 (Carton 3, Folder 42)
- "The Responsibility of Ownership," UC-Davis, 10/12/89 (Carton 3, Folder 43)
- "U.S. Business Can Get The Job Done In Australia," 11/29/89, Investment Seminar on Australia, Los Angeles (Carton 3, Folder 44)
- "Pacific Trade: Bid and Complex," Pacific Rim Forum, 4/25/90, SF (Carton 3, Folder 45)
- Idaho Governor's Centennial Conf. Keynote Address, 3/4/90 (Carton 3, Folder 46)
- Correspondence re: Oral History Examples (Carton 4, Folder 1)
- "How Sunset Magazine Subscribers Evaluate the Magazines they Read: A Study of Magazine Preferences," Faville, David E. Prof of Marketing, GSB, Stanford University, 1940. (Carton 4, Folder 2)
- "Sunset: the History of a Successful Regional Magazine," Mulhall, Charles W., MA thesis, SU, 1955. (Carton 4, Folder 3)
- Lane Publishing Company Archives: Master files and Sub-files (Carton 4, Folder 4)
- Sunset - Oral History: newspaper articles re "Oral History" (Carton 4, Folder 5)
- Sunset - Oral History: interviewee list (Carton 4, Folder 6)
- Sunset - Oral History: proposal - B. Campbell (Carton 4, Folder 7)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Ruth Lane (Carton 4, Folder 8)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Walter Doty (Carton 4, Folder 9)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Pat James Lyman (Carton 4, Folder 10)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Ken Copperidge (Carton 4, Folder 11)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Don Campbell (Carton 4, Folder 12)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Norm Gordon (Carton 4, Folder 13)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Mel Lane (Carton 4, Folder 14)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Harold Mathis (Carton 4, Folder 15)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Martin Lipton (Carton 4, Folder 16)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Al Le Conte (Carton 4, Folder 17)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Elsa Knoll (Carton 4, Folder 18)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Proctor Mellquist (Carton 4, Folder 19)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Bill McGrew (Carton 4, Folder 20)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Ebba Pehrson (Carton 4, Folder 21)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - George Pfeieffer (Carton 4, Folder 22)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Lou Harrison, Gen Callahan (Carton 4, Folder 23)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Howard Willoughby (Carton 4, Folder 24)
- Sunset - Oral History -[Correspondence] (Carton 4, Folder 25)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Dave Clark (Dick Dunmire, interviewer) (Carton 4, Folder 26)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Cliff May (Daniel Gregory, interviewer) (Carton 4, Folder 27)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Harry Wong (Stan Garvey and Don Campbell, interviewers) (Carton 4, Folder 28)
- Sunset - Oral History: transcript - Newcomb (Buck) Shaw (Don Campbell and Bill McGrew, interviewers) (Carton 4, Folder 29)
- Sunset - Oral History: tapes - audiocassettes separated from folders 26-29. (Carton 4, Folder 30)
- "Yosemite: Inspiration, Success, and Challenge," Yosemite, October 13, 1990. (Carton 5, Folder 1)
- Yosemite Centennial Gala, MC Comments, 11/14/1990, St. Francis (Carton 5, Folder 2)
- The Communication Explosion helped Defuse the Nuclear Explosion - U of O[regon] - 1/22/91 (Carton 5, Folder 3)
- What's Ahead in the Americas? - ANZ Bank, Mar 23, 1991 (Carton 5, Folder 4)
- Robust Tourism/Global Health - PATA, Bali 4/9/91 (Carton 5, Folder 5)
- "Challenge in the Pacific" - Commencement - Hawaii Loa 5/25/91 (Carton 5, Folder 6)
- Opening Remarks - 75th Anniversary of the NPS - Vail, Colorado 10-7-91 (Carton 5, Folder 7)
- A Few Observations on International Banking - ANZ Bank, Melbourne March 3, 1992 (Carton 5, Folder 8)
- Pacific Rim trade, Tourism, and Jobs - So. Oregon State College, 5-15-1992 (Carton 5, Folder 9)
- Yes, Crystal, there really are Angels - Valley Presbyterian Church, 12-224-1992 (Carton 5, Folder 10)
- The Pacific Century Marches On to a Different Beat - NASBITE - Portland, Ore, 3-25-1993 (Carton 5, Folder 11)
- "PATA sets a Pioneer Role for APEC" January 28-29,1994 (Carton 5, Folder 12)
- Vision Makes the World Go 'Round - NPCA 75th Anniversary May 18, 1994 (Carton 5, Folder 13)
- The End of the Beginning - Jakarta, Indonesia, Dec 5, 1994 (Carton 5, Folder 14)
- Special Park Legislative Hearing "Can we protect today's investment?", Sacramento, CA, 3-19-1996 (Carton 5, Folder 15)
- Imperative Alliance - AAA - Sydney, July 2, 1996 (Carton 5, Folder 16)
- 1997: A Window of Opportunity for the Environment - Asilomar, 1/5/1997 (Carton 5, Folder 17)
- Introduction of Jane Goodall - POST Lecture, May 6, 1997 (Carton 5, Folder 18)
- Testimony/US Senate Sub-Committee - National Parks/Presidio, Nov 19,1997 (Carton 5, Folder 19)
- Celebration Past and Future of Magazine Publishing - Century of Sunset - Medill School, 5-5-1998 (Carton 5, Folder 20)
- Robert Redford Introduction - POST lecture series, 3/1/1999 (Carton 5, Folder 21)
- PATA'S Proud Past\DestinationDestination[?] Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, April 9, 2001 (Carton 5, Folder 22)
- Yes, Crystal, there really are Angels - Christmas, 2002 (Carton 5, Folder 23)
- "Down Memory Lane" - New Town Center - Groundbreaking, PV, April 28, 2007 (Carton 5, Folder 24)
- Boyhood Companions; Celebration for Mel, September 11, 2007 (Carton 5, Folder 25)
- Foreign Travel and Climate Change - Foreign Travel Club of SF, 1/24/2008 (Carton 5, Folder 26)
- Acceptance - Dr. of Humane Letters - Cal Poly, June 15, 2008 (Carton 5, Folder 27)
- San Mateo County History Maker, 9/25/2008 (Carton 5, Folder 28)
- Get It Right/Lincoln and the West - Bill Lane Center, Stanford - 2/5/2009 (Carton 5, Folder 29)
- Statement, Commonwealth Club Gala, April 17, 2009 (Carton 5, Folder 30)
- Saturday Review - "The Golden Glow of Sunset" - March 13,1965 (Carton 5, Folder 31)
- "The Wise Ones in Menlo Park" - Diner's Club Magazine, 4/1968 (Carton 5, Folder 32)
- PA Times, Jan. 22, 1970 - YPC Board (Carton 5, Folder 33)
- Pacific Business - One Man's Opinion, May-June 1972 (Carton 5, Folder 34)
- Nation's Business - "L.W. Lane Jr. of Sunset", January, 1973 (Carton 5, Folder 35)
- LA Times - Sunset Magazine - Gold From the Ground Roots, 6/24/1973. (Carton 5, Folder 36)
- Wal Street Journal, "The Scions," 1/17/1975 (Carton 5, Folder 37)
- Press Release: US Commissioner General for International Ocean Exposition, 3/10/1975 (Carton 5, Folder 38)
- Peninsula Magazine, "Bill Lane: Inside Sunset's Empire," October, 1977 (Carton 5, Folder 39)
- Chicago Tribune, "Fastest Draw (of trends) in West Sets Our Style," 11/23/1977 (Carton 5, Folder 40)
- SF Examiner, "A Magazine's Dawn," Dwight Chapin, 7/7/1978 (Carton 5, Folder 41)
- SF Chronicle, "Behind Sunset's Healthy Glow," 7/15/1978 (Carton 5, Folder 42)
- California Living, "Bill Lane's Magical Gardens," 5/13/1979 (Carton 5, Folder 43)
- Travel Age West, 10th Anniversary Editorial, July 30, 1979 (Carton 5, Folder 44)
- LA Times, "The Sun Never Sets on the Lanes' Western Empire,"12/7/1980 (Carton 5, Folder 45)
- [US Postal Service "Tourism Aerogram" Issuance, 12/29/1980, clippings, invitation] (Carton 5, Folder 46)
- California Today, "Sun Shines on the Sunset Empire," 4/26/1981 (Carton 5, Folder 47)
- SF Sunday Examiner and Chronicle, "Great Magazines," Kevin Starr, 1/17/1982 (Carton 5, Folder 48)
- SF Business Journal, "Sunset: Publishing Success Story," 1/25/1982 (Carton 5, Folder 49)
- Historic Hawai'I News, "Conservation is Vital to Tourism Says Publisher," 7/82 (Carton 5, Folder 50)
- USA Today, Cover Story "On Taking the Pulse of USA Regions," 1/21/1983 (Carton 5, Folder 51)
- Palo Alto Weekly, "Behind the Success of Sunset Magazine," 5/23/1984 (Carton 5, Folder 52)
- Country Almanac, "Bill Lane Bullish on Australia," 3/11/1987 (Carton 5, Folder 53)
- Peninsula Magazine, "Empire of the Sunset," 4/1988 (Carton 5, Folder 54)
- The Printer, "Sunset and Donnelley," Winter, 1989 (Carton 5, Folder 55)
- STET, "Mel Lane Welcomes?Bill Lane," May, 1989 (Carton 5, Folder 56)
- Canberra Times, 4/15/1989 (Carton 5, Folder 57)
- Country Almanac, 6/14/1989 (Carton 5, Folder 58)
- Country Almanac, 6/21/1989 (Carton 5, Folder 59)
- LA Times, 6/19/1989 (Carton 5, Folder 60)
- SF Chronicle, 7/29/1989 (Carton 5, Folder 61)
- Peninsula Horseman, 1/7/1989 (Carton 5, Folder 62)
- Peninsula Times Tribune, 5/25/ 1989 (Carton 5, Folder 63)
- San Mateo Times, 7/23/1989 (Carton 5, Folder 64)
- Sydney Daily Telegraph, 3/23/1989 (Carton 5, Folder 65)
- Weekend Australian, "?wins hearts of Island children," October, 1986 (Carton 5, Folder 66)
- Country Almanac, "B. Lane in Antarctica" (Carton 5, Folder 67)
- Hawaiian Beat, "We've Come A Long Way, Partner," 2/1989 (Carton 5, Folder 68)
- The Bulletin with Newsweek, 2/21/1989 (pg 91) (Carton 5, Folder 69)
- Editorial Times Tribune, "GOP Crew Shouldn't Abandon Ship," 10/30/1992 (Carton 5, Folder 70)
- San Jose Mercury, "At Home With Bill and Jean Lane," 4/9/1993 (Carton 5, Folder 71)
- Folio Magazine, "Champion of Quality," 6/1/1993 (Carton 5, Folder 72)
- International Herald Tribune, "Opinion: Sydney Olympics," 9/10/1993 (Carton 5, Folder 73)
- Country Almanac, "Bill Lane Honored for Support of NPs," 6/8/1994 (Carton 5, Folder 74)
- Almanac, "Portola Valley Turns 30," 6/15/1994 (Carton 5, Folder 75)
- SF Chronicle, Feinstein and Wilson Letter to the Editor, 11/7/1994 (Carton 5, Folder 76)
- Country Almanac, "Passion for Parks," 3/15/1995 (Carton 5, Folder 77)
- Misc Articles, 1995 (Carton 5, Folder 78)
- San Mateo County Times, "Former Sunset Publisher Sizes Up California," 7/22/1996 (Carton 5, Folder 79)
- Oakland Tribune, "Adventurer's Next Trip: Space,"4/6/1998 (Carton 5, Folder 80)
- Country Almanac, Ormondale School Education Center, 11/27/1996 (Carton 5, Folder 81)
- Almanac, "Sunset Past and Present," 4/22/1998 (Carton 5, Folder 82)
- Almanac, Letter to the Editor, 6/17/1998 (Carton 5, Folder 83)
- Palo Alto Historical Society, "My Life in Palo Alto," 10/1998 (Carton 5, Folder 84)
- San Jose Mercury News, Voice Article, 3/17/1999 (Carton 5, Folder 85)
- Sierra Magazine, "Urban Legends," Jan-Feb/2000 (Carton 5, Folder 86)
- Almanac, "Bill Lane Near Poterntial Ground Zero," 9/19/2001 (Carton 5, Folder 87)
- Almanac, "fight Back With Your Vote," 10/10/2001 (Carton 5, Folder 88)
- Almanac, Maximo Martinez Auction, 7/3/2003 (Carton 5, Folder 89)
- Almanac, "Bill Lane to Advise Schwarze on Environment," 10/29/2003 (Carton 5, Folder 90)
- CSPF News Release, "Emergency Relief Fund," 10/31/2003 (Carton 5, Folder 91)
- Almanac,"50 Years Santa," 12/03/2003 (Carton 5, Folder 92)
- Almanac,"Portola Valley at 40," 6/9/2004 (Carton 5, Folder 93)
- Almanac,"Valley's Rural Space Alive and Well," 11/19/2003 (Carton 5, Folder 94)
- Almanac, Reagan and Lane, 6/119/2004 (Carton 5, Folder 95)
- Almanac, "Lane Gives $5 Million to Stanford," 3/2/2005 (Carton 5, Folder 96)
- Sunset April 2005, Sierra Club Ad (Carton 5, Folder 97)
- Gentry, "Bill Lane Center for the Study of the West," July 2005 (Carton 5, Folder 98)
- Almanac, "Lanes' honored at 'Blues and Barbecue,'" 8/31/2005 (Carton 5, Folder 99)
- Almanac, SF Mercury News, Conservation Easement, 12/20/2006, 12/18/2006 (Carton 5, Folder 100)
- SF Chronicle, Opinion piece, national Parks, 6/9/2007 (Carton 5, Folder 101)
- Almanac, "Fond Thoughts About Almanac and Carol Ivie," 6/29/2005 (Carton 5, Folder 102)
- Almanac, "New $500K Matching Grant," August, 2007 (Carton 5, Folder 103)
- Redwood City Daily, "Lane Family Western History makers," 10/8/2008 (Carton 5, Folder 104)
- Almanac, "Bill Lane is Still Going Strong," 11/4/2009 (Carton 5, Folder 105)
- Mustang Daily, "Former Ambassador Addresses Students on the Economy," 1/27/2010 (Carton 5, Folder 106)
- Speech Tour, October 1988 AAF, Comst. Club, Linc Club, PSC and VB (Carton 5, Folder 107)
- Visit of Parliamentary Joint Committee on Foreign Affairs and Defense, [September, 1987] (Carton 5, Folder 108)
- Mr. and Mrs. Lane Presentation Portrait (Duplicate), Open Reel Sony videotape 1/2" (Carton 6, Folder 1)
- Art Modin Interview by Binny Blechman: 3 audiocassettes; 2 copies of transcripts (Carton 6, Folder 2)
- Jim Webb, interviewed by Don Campbell, May 1990; notes, 2 audiocassettes (Carton 6, Folder 3)
- Proc Mellquist, interviewed by Bill Marken/Joe Williamson, Feb. 1989; 2 copies of transcripts, notes, 9 audiocassettes [1 of 2] (Carton 6, Folder 4)
- Proc Mellquist, interviewed by Bill Marken/Joe Williamson, Feb. 1989; 2 copies of transcripts, notes, 9 audiocassettes [2 of 2] (Carton 6, Folder 5)
- Transcript: Elsa Knoll, interviewed by BC [?], july 30, 1980; correspondence; office memo re: reorganizing Book Division, April 24, 1989 (Carton 6, Folder 6)
- Oral History Project "Archives" (Carton 6, Folder 7)
- Portrait Presentation, Original 10-8-1966 (Carton 6, Folder 8)
- Hary Wong interview, by Stan Garvey, 3/7/1989, Audiocassette (Carton 6, Folder 9)
- Sunset 75th Anniversary material: Picture of entire Sunset staff; pictures of totem poles; small photos of old illustrations in Sunset ad, SF Chronicle, 4/25/1973; miscellaneous items (Carton 6, Folder 10)
- Newspaper and magazines carrying Sunset 75th Anniversary Ad (Carton 6, Folder 11)
- Returns of material from Newcomen Society re: The Sunset Story?. (Carton 7, Folder 1)
- The Sunset Story Address and Booklet, May 15, 1969 (Carton 7, Folder 2)
- VIP Christmas Luncheon, December 13, 1977 [photographs] (Carton 7, Folder 3)
- Sunset's Millionth Visitor (Carton 7, Folder 4)
- 50th Anniversary of Lane Publishing Co. [1979] Miscellaneous (Carton 7, Folder 5)
- 50th Anniversary of Lane Publishing Co. February 1979 Sunset Anniversary Issue (Carton 7, Folder 6)
- 50th Anniversary of Lane Publishing Co. Press Clippings (Carton 7, Folder 7)
- 80th Anniversary of Sunset 1898-1978: Press Kit (Carton 7, Folder 8)
- 80th Anniversary of Sunset 1898-1978: Media Correspondence and Clippings (Carton 7, Folder 9)
- 80th Anniversary of Sunset 1898-1978: 1898 Silver Dollars (Carton 7, Folder 10)
- 80th Anniversary of Sunset 1898-1978: Advertisement (Carton 7, Folder 11)
- 80th Anniversary of Sunset 1898-1978: Congratulatory Letters (Carton 7, Folder 12)
- 80th Anniversary of Sunset 1898-1978: Miscellaneous (Carton 7, Folder 13)
- 75th Anniversary of Sunset 1898-1973: Miscellaneous (Carton 7, Folder 14)